ualmiles.com 2007-07-15

# United Airlines - Privacy Policy

**Your privacy is important to us**

We want you to know that when you use one of the UAL family Internet Web sites, and when you provide us with information off-line, the privacy of your personally identifiable information will be respected and protected.  While United strives to take reasonable measures to protect the privacy of our customers, this Privacy Policy is not a contract and does not create any legal rights or obligations.  Rather, the following are guidelines for protecting the information you provide to us.

With respect to online transactions, this Privacy Policy applies to transactions conducted within the United States on united.com, flyted.com, and any other web site within the UAL family (“United”).  This policy does not apply to United Cargo transactions, including those conducted on unitedcargo.com.  For the privacy policies of web sites outside of the UAL family, like United Vacations, Orbitz, Travelocity, or Expedia, please see their web sites for the policies that apply.

**What information do we collect?**

United collects and maintains personally identifiable information about customers through our web sites and through off-line transactions such as over the telephone, through a United reservations agent or other travel agent, and in person at United counters or at the Red Carpet Club.  Personally identifiable information includes, but is not limited to, your name, address, passport number, credit card numbers, phone numbers, and email address.  In addition, when you use our web sites, certain user information and site activity data is collected.  Further details on the information we collect is described below.

Mileage Plus® information

When you [enroll in Mileage Plus](http://www.united.com/join), or if you are already a Mileage Plus member, we collect specific information such as your name, address, phone numbers, email address, Mileage Plus number, password and a password reminder.

Traveler’s profile information

When you enroll in Mileage Plus or activate your Mileage Plus account, an optional traveler profile can be created for your convenience. You are not required to complete a profile to use our web sites for your reservations.  In order to complete your traveler’s profile, the following information may be requested:  credit card type, number, expiration date and billing address, telephone numbers, email addresses, general requests or special needs, travel preferences and loyalty program information.

On-line purchases

It is not required that you be a Mileage Plus member, activate your Mileage Plus account on one of our web sites, or complete a traveler's profile in order to make reservations on one of our web sites. However, Mileage Plus membership and a traveler's profile will allow you to complete a reservation more quickly and give you online access to your Mileage Plus account information, past transactions, and special services. If you purchase as a guest, information such as billing, contact, and preferences will be collected in order to execute the transaction.

Promotions

We occasionally sponsor promotions to give members the opportunity to win various prizes. Information collected for promotions can include contact information, such as email address, and survey questions.

Cookies

By using one of our web sites, some information may  automatically be collected by our web servers as you browse our site.  United also collects information by using technologies and methodologies that enable tracking, such as “cookies”. 

Cookies are small bits of information that are stored on your computer by your web browser.  Web beacons (also called "pixel tags") are small strings of code placed on a web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring information.  Cookies help establish a user session and allow our server to correctly provide site users with the appropriate information, advertisements and services.  

Domain names

In general, you can visit most parts of our web sites without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself.  Our web servers identify the domain names and IP addresses of visitors, where applicable, but this is not captured as personally identifiable information.  

Off-line purchases:  Reservations by telephone, travel agent,  

or ticket counter

In order to book your reservation with a United reservations agent, a travel agent (including online travel agents outside of the UAL family), or a customer service representative (collectively, “Reservations Agents”), Reservations Agents collect data such as credit card numbers, passport numbers, birth date, name, addresses, email addresses, and telephone numbers.  Telephone calls to Reservations Agents may be monitored and/or recorded and by continuing with the call, you are deemed to consent to such monitoring and/or recording.

Red Carpet Club

United may collect personally identifiable information such as name, addresses, email addresses, telephone numbers, and credit card numbers, in order to provide service to members of its Red Carpet Club.

In-flight

If a medical or other emergency occurs while onboard, boarding, or disembarking a United aircraft, United may share customer information with third-party medical or other safety personnel as necessary.  Additionally, United may collect credit card and Mileage Plus information in-flight to enable present and/or future purchases.

Children

United does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13.  However, due to the nature of our services, travel purchase information may be collected without requiring the customer to disclose his or her age.  If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide personal information of any kind whatsoever on our websites.  If a child provides us with personally identifiable information online without our knowledge, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us by sending an email to [web-mpi@united.com](mailto:web-mpi@united.com), or by calling 1-800-421-4655 if they would like this information deleted from our records.  However, we retain information necessary to provide transportation to a child under 13.

**How do we use your information?**

We do not intend to use your personally identifiable information collected through this site or off-line in ways not described here without first providing you the opportunity to opt-out of that use.

United uses personal information collected in conjunction with registration or purchases on our web sites and off-line purchases and transactions to complete transactions and fulfill requests for services.  We also use your personal information to provide you with a more effective customer experience.  In order to do this, United may process your information or combine it with other information that we have about you or that is publicly available.  In addition, United may share this information with third parties for the purpose of providing you with services, information or promotional opportunities that may be of interest to you.  We require strict contractual obligations from these third parties to ensure safeguards for the privacy and security of the information which are at least as restrictive as this Privacy Policy in handling your information.

Information collected during transactions

  We provide information collected from you to airlines, car rental agencies, hotels, travel agencies or other contracted third parties to facilitate the successful fulfillment of your travel arrangements or for the specific purpose for which you provided the information. As an added service, subject to your opting out as described below, your purchase behavior may also be analyzed to identify and present offers that may be of interest to you. 

Mileage Plus®

Information collected from Mileage Plus members is used to enroll you in Mileage Plus and ensure that you receive applicable mileage credit for travel purchases for participating flights and other Mileage Plus participating vendor (partner) activities. This information is also used to communicate with you on your Mileage Plus account status and notify you of any special promotions for which you might be eligible. On occasion, we may provide customer mailing list and email addresses to reputable, carefully-screened Mileage Plus partners or other companies whose services or products may be of interest to you. (You may unsubscribe by Opting-Out, as described below.) Sharing of customer lists may also provide you with the opportunity to earn bonus miles for non-flight activity. As indicated, we require strict contractual obligations from these third parties to ensure safeguards for the privacy and security of the information which are at least as restrictive as this Privacy Policy in handling your information.

Traveler’s profile information

We use traveler’s profile information to perform a number of functions including 1) pre-filling certain data fields to eliminate you from having to type the same information multiple times 2) performing certain booking functions, 3) billing you for your reservation, 4) sending you offers that may be of value unless you opt out, as described below and 5) notifying you of a flight change, reservation confirmation or a special fare offering.

Emails

We use email addresses to deliver information relevant to our customers, such as fare specials, reservation confirmations, surveys, account information, notification services, and for administrative reasons.  As a Mileage Plus member, a registered user of one of our web sites, or contest entrant, you occasionally will receive emails about fare sales, special offers, new services and other noteworthy news items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Of course, if you would rather not receive this information, you may opt-out of receiving such emails as described below

Online surveys and promotions

We value the opinions of our customers and want to improve your travel experience and our service offerings; therefore, from time to time, we will conduct research surveys. We may also contract with third parties to perform the research, but the use of the customer data by that third party is limited solely to that survey initiative and is protected by a confidentiality agreement.

Generally, unless otherwise stated in the promotion or survey, contact information collected for promotions is used to notify promotion winners, and survey information and results are used to develop improved promotions and other service enhancements.

Flight status alerts/Wireless services

Our customers can register for Flight status alerts and other wireless services by providing basic flight information and other relevant information. Wherever possible, information already provided will be used for the delivery of these services. Participation in Flight status alerts and other wireless services is optional.

Cookies

Cookies help establish a user session and allow our server to correctly provide site users with the appropriate information, advertisements and services.  We also use cookies to ensure you obtain the information you request and to authenticate your authority to access the site.  If you are a registered user on our site and you elect to have the site store your Mileage Plus number, the cookie stored on your computer will contain your Mileage Plus number. We also use cookies to track the usage of our web sites in order to improve the site according to our customers’ needs. 

United may enter into agreements with third party companies to serve advertisements and information to site users. United may use its cookies when working with these companies to provide them information regarding use of the site or to serve you advertisements when you visit our site.  These companies may use the non-personally identifiable information about your visit to make available goods and services of interest to you.

In addition, some third-party advertising technology used by United to deliver advertisements may employ a separate cookie.  This technology uses non-personally identifiable information about your visits to this web site and the web sites upon which we advertise in order to serve ads to you. Web beacons on some pages of our site, in conjunction with these advertising cookies, enable the third party advertising technology to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits this site, and to learn which banner ads bring users to our web site. If you do not want your non-personally identifiable information to be used to serve ads to you, you can change the settings on your Internet browser to reject cookies. Please consult your chosen Internet browser for instructions on how to change your cookie handling settings.

If you are a registered user on our site and you elect to have the site store your Mileage Plus number, the cookie stored on your computer will contain your Mileage Plus number.  While most people accept cookies, you can configure your browser to not accept cookies from us or from third party companies, like the third party ad servers. If you choose not to accept our cookies, however, and are a registered user, you will not have access to your personal information on this site such as your user profile, itineraries, award travel, upgrades and Mileage Plus summary information. Although you cannot log into the site as a registered user if you disable our cookies, you can still purchase on the site by logging in as a guest.

Domain names

Information regarding domain names is aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed and similar site usage information in order to know how to improve the site's content.

Children

No information we collect from children known to be under the age of 13 is used for any marketing or promotional purposes whatsoever, by either us, our affiliates, or our third party sponsors. We use the information collected about children known to be under 13 only to provide services.  We will give out personal information about children if required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena or to protect the safety and security of visitors and our sites.

Law Enforcement/Legal processes/Other uses

United may disclose personal information if required to do so by law, court order, subpoena or other legal process, as requested by a governmental or law enforcement authority, or when we believe in good faith that it is in the interests of aviation security or that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable. 

**How can you access your information?**

If you are registered on one of our web sites, you can create, [view or update your Traveler’s Profile](http://www.united.com/updateprofile) and Mileage Plus account by accessing them through the UAL family web site Log-in.  If you are not registered on one of our web sites, you can review and request changes to your personally identifiable information collected by United by calling 1-800-421-4655.

**How is the information collected online protected?**

United maintains strict physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect personal information and regularly reviews its security standards and procedures to protect against unauthorized access to personal information.  When you place orders to purchase services or access your Mileage Plus account information, we use secure servers to protect your personal information.  Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software encrypts the personal information that is transmitted between you and our web sites.

Although United takes reasonable steps to safeguard and to prevent unauthorized access to your private information, it cannot be responsible for the acts of those who gain unauthorized access, and United makes no warranty, express, implied, or otherwise, that we will prevent unauthorized access to your private information.

**How can you opt out?**

If you do not want United to use or share your personal information for the purpose of sending you email  marketing or promotional materials, please go to the UAL family web site you are using and update your email preferences accordingly.  In addition, emails sent to you will also contain a message on how to opt out of that type of communication in the future.  Regardless of your opt-out preferences, we reserve the right to send you emails or other electronic messages for administrative purposes. 

**Other sites**

This Privacy Policy, to the extent it covers Internet use, covers only the UAL family web sites and does not cover any other site, including those related to this site such as unitedvacations.com, unitedcargo.com or the non-U.S. United sites. While we make every effort to protect your information on our web sites, we do not control the policies of other sites (including those we may link to).  We have no control over other sites' privacy policies or use of any personal information you or others may share with them.  Please do not assume that our Privacy Policy covers those other sites.

**Protect your personal information**

In order to protect your privacy and United’s proprietary databases and systems, we recommend that you not share any of your personally identifiable information, such as Mileage Plus number or password, with any third-party information aggregators that would allow them access to sensitive account information.

**How can you contact us?**

If you have comments or questions about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [customervoice9@united.com](mailto:customervoice9@united.com).  Please reference this Privacy Policy in those communications.

**Legal effect and changes to the policy**

As indicated, this Privacy Policy is not a contract nor does it otherwise create any legal rights or obligations.  Rather, this Privacy Policy merely reflects guidelines setting forth United’s intended business practices.  However, by using this web site, and/or by providing personal information to United online or off-line, you consent to the collection and use of such information by United, its affiliates, partners, contractors and permitted agents consistent with applicable laws.  Also, United, in its discretion, may amend, interpret, modify, or withdraw any portion of this Privacy Policy and related business practices at any time by posting updated text on this site, and your continued use constitutes your consent to those changes.    A version of this Privacy Policy has been effective since October 15, 2002, and was last updated in November, 2006.  Thank you for taking the time to read this Privacy Policy.
